## **GRAHAM A. SCHMIDT**

schmidtg@gmail.com http://www.schmidtg.com

Software Engineer: Over 10+ years experience in web development, programming, graphic design and team leadership. I'm constantly self-learning and challenging myself everyday to be the most effective software engineer. I take pride in delivering results, and I communicate proactively to ensure that expectations are met regularly.

#### **RELEVANT SKILLS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Specialties: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Javascript/Ajax, Angular, jQuery, HTML/CSS, Git, MVC, PHP, MySQL, Internet technologies
- Passion for developing seemless User experiences that leverage innovative web technologies
- Dedicated and hard-working individual who delivers polished results every time
- Highly self-motivated and constantly looking to make things better

## **RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer

May 2013 – Present

WorldOne Interactive

- Develop new features and fix various defects for a large Rails application (Sermo.com)
- Write tests, specs as part of test-driven development best practice

# Back-end Engineer

September 2011 – April 2013

Hungry Fish Media, LLC / NutraClick

- · Write, maintain and optimize PHP scripts to handle automation and management of large datasets
- Lead developer for Magento Enterprise e-commerce site (www.healthexperts.com)
- Built various support tools for handling management of 15,000+ SKU catalog
- Shared lead development (Zend) for building self-serve 'Membership' site of 30,000+ users
- · Earned greater responsibility for independently managing the completion of major projects

## Senior Front-End Engineer

September 2010 – September 2011

Hungry Fish Media, LLC

- Built numerous business tools and reports using the Flourish PHP framework, AJAX, and custom javascript namespaced objects
- Rigorously tested and improved landing pages on a daily basis using an in-house analytics A/B testing platform along with Google Analytics
- Refactored existing codebase to be more object-oriented for greater code reuse
- Crafted hand-coded pages (VIM, Chrome Dev, Firebug) in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript for superior readability, rapid development and ease of maintenance
- Progressed to senior front-end developer after only 6 months in the front-end role, and co-ordinated the hiring of new team members and taking on senior duties

# Graphic Designer

September 2009 – September 2010

Hungry Fish Media, LLC

- Regularly created numerous Landing Pages and web advertisements for display on large websites such as MSN.com, Yahoo.com, and AOL which generated some of the highest click-thru rates and lead acquisitions in the company's history
- Created a successful landing page in one work day that went on to become the fastest growing lead acquisition website by the company
- Created various print, promotional and packaging materials that helped establish one of the top selling nutritional sports supplement brands in GNC stores nationwide

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, PHP, Coffeescript, SASS, LESS, C, Java, PostgreSQL, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3,

RegEx, Bash, XML, Actionscript

Editors: Sublime, Vim

Databases/Servers: PostgresSQL, MySQL, Apache, Mac OS X

Frameworks/Libraries: Rails, Angular, jQuery, jQuery mobile, Twitter Bootstrap, Prototype, Backbone.js,

Underscore.js, Zend, Flourish (PHP), Codelgniter, Laravel

Testing Tools: Rspec, TestUnit, Jasmine, Chrome Dev Tools, Firebug, Selenium, Grunt

Concepts: UX/UI architecture, Front-end engineering, Responsive design, TDD, Agile, MVC, AJAX, OOP, JSON, Single-page Apps, Version control (Git), REST, Database design, Agile, Scrum, SEO, CMS, Big Data,

Visualization, Web architecture, Functional programming

#### RECENT PERSONAL PROJECT URLS

Saskhighland.ca (responsive) <a href="http://www.saskhighland.ca/">http://www.saskhighland.ca/</a>

LexPress mobile app (PHP, JS, jQuery mobile) <a href="http://www.schmidtg.com/lexpress/app/">http://www.schmidtg.com/lexpress/app/</a>

Eventry.net registration system (Codeigniter) <a href="http://www.eventry.net/">http://www.eventry.net/</a>
CMAP LLC (Wordpress) <a href="http://www.cmapllc.com/">http://www.cmapllc.com/</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

Graduate-Level Coursework

2011 - Present

Harvard University Extension School (Cambridge, MA)

• Java for Distributed Computing, Data structures, Intensive Intro to CS (pre-reg)

**Bsc Computer Science** (great distinction, \*85% average) Awarded 2005 \*My university does not use grade-point average but instead gives an overall percentage University of Regina (Canada)

Software Engineering, Human Computer Interaction, Visualization, Databases

## Multimedia Certificate

Awarded 2003

Applied Multimedia Centre (Canada)

• Graphic design, page layout, typography, sound editing, 3D animation

### TRANSFERABLE SKILLS

- Fast learner and incredibly resourceful
- Excellent communication skills
- Able to manage time and resources efficiently
- Independent, reliable and very hard-working

## **ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS**

Adventure travel, cooking, hiking, homebrewing, bagpiping

### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request